

tl;dr_

Software engineer with 5 years of experience, fascination for intriguing computer science problems and a flair for Systems programming & Site Reliability. Believes in using the right tool for the right job. Finds home coding in Python and talking about Clojure.

Experience _

Quick Algorithm Srl Milan, Italy

TECH LEAD April 2018 - Present

I help develop the scalable infrastructure for the data crunching algorithms that the company offer as a service. My job involves deploying and managing the infrastructure which includes our own data vizualization platform and several pipelines for.

Pears Remote

CORE DEVELOPER

July 2016 - Present

PeARS is a free and open source, distributed, and lightweight search engine using distributional semantics technique. The project has been funded so far by the University of Cambridge and the Mozilla foundation. Develops critical components of the product.

Red Hat Inc.

Bangalore, India

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (PYTHON, C)

January 2015 - June 2016

Worked as a member of the Gluster filesystem development team. Wrote features and tools both in C and Python to improve the performance and usability of the product.

Bang The Table Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, India

RUBY ON RAILS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

May 2014 - Dec. 2014

Implemented many enhancement features like survey, pools, etc. to the community engagement platform EngagementHQ for Australian, New Zealand, and Canadian Govt. Worked with the customer support team to fix core product issues by meeting SLAs

Projects & Open Source Contributions

- Tweefka Developed a twitter like streaming web app, which uses Kafka as a message broker and 2019 Developer socket.io to broker and render real time streaming data. **Gdeploy** - Developed a tool to set-up and deploy GlusterFS using ansible over multiple hosts. 2016 Core Developer Wrote and maintained numerous Ansible modules for the upstream Ansible repository. Automated Rendering Testing - As a part of the Google Summer of Code project, wrote a tool to 2013 test the rendering of fonts by engine in Python for the organization Swathanthra Malayalam Core Developer Computing. Programmatic creation of PDF books from HTML pages for non-latin scripts - A Python project to implement PDF exports of HTML content like wiki pages for non-latin scripts like all Indic 2014 Developer
- Other Achievements & Awards

languages, Arabic etc.

- University of Cambridge sponsorship The PeARS team was invited over to the University of
- 2016 Cambridge to be a part of the workshop series on Open source and NLP and to meet and work with the team face-to-face.
- 2014 **Google Women Techmaker India** Was one among the 10 winners of Women Techmaker award given away by Google
- 2013 **Linux foundation training scholarship** Won the Linux Foundation Training Scholarship awarded only to 5 people around the world under the category System Administration WhizKid
- 2013 **Red Hat scholarship** Won a scholarship from Red Hat, where I was completely sponsored to attend the RHCSA training
- Google Summer of Code Successfully implemented a framework in Python to automatically test
 the fonts rendered by engines as the Google Summer of Code project under the organization
 Swathanthra Malayalam Computing in the domain Natural Language Processing

Trainings & Certifications

2017	Recurse Center - Got selected for a 3 month programmers' retreat in which computer science enthusiasts from all around the world participated and exchanged knowdledge	New York City
2013	Linux Foundation System Administration certification - Completed the Linux Foundation sys admin course	Remote
2013	Red Hat Certified System Administration course(RHCSA) - Completed RHCSA training covering advanced topics in system administration	Bangalore, India

Presentations & Talks

- 2016 Git internals and how to get involved in open source projects using it University of Cambridge
- 2014 Open Source contributions what and how? College of Engineering, Munnar
- 2014 **Deterministic parallel programming with Haskell** NSS College of Engineering, Palakkad, India
- 2013 Unicode fonts and it's testing SMC 12th year event, Thrissur, India
- 2013 Introduction to Open Source Contributions Devcon, Model Engineering College, India
- 2013 Swathanthra Malayalam Computing An introduction PMG HSS, PKD, India
- 2013 Free and Open Source software An Introduction Women's polytechnic college, Payyannur
- 2013 Rubygem packaging for Debian FOSSMeet NIT Calicut, India

Education

Politecnico Di Milano Milano, Italy

MASTER OF SCIENCE(LAUREA MAGISTRALE) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

September 2017 - 2020

NSS College of Engineering (affiliated to the University of Calicut)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Palakkad, India Mar. 2010 - April 2014

Technical Skills

Programming Languages - Python, Clojure, C, Ruby, Java, Elixir

Operating Systems - GNU/Linux (Fedora, Debian and its derivatives, Arch Linux, & similar Linus distros)

Languages - Python, Clojure, Elixir, C, Ruby, Go(Basics), HTML/CSS/Javascript(working knowledge), Java(basics)

Infrastructure dev tools - Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, AWS and GCP stacks, Ansible, OpenStack, MediaWiki, MySQL, Harfbuzz, LaTeX, Gimp, Scrapy, Twisted

Data managemen and processing - Different RDBMS and NoSQL flavours, Elasticsearch, Kafka, Spark, Flink, TinyOS